Patrick Mounts

503.679.8657 | patrickmnts@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/patrickmnts Github: www.github.com/patrickmnts Portfolio: www.patrickmnts.com

Professional Summary

- Enthusiastic and ambitious junior web-developer prepared for transition to full-time web development
- Bright, loyal, and excited to rapidly continue learning industry best practices

Technical Experience

Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap & Responsive Designs,

Git/Github, Ruby, Chrome Dev. Tools

Programming Skills: Agile Methods, TDD, Paired Programming, Pull Requests, API's, JSON &

XML, OOP

Frameworks: Rails, Sinatra, *currently learning Drupal

Professional Experience

Portland Code School - Portland, OR

06/2013 - 08/2013

Jr. Web Developer

- 3 month intensive course building necessary skills for success as a Junior Developer
- Built and examined entire lifespan of applications from concept through stable deployment
- Managed team development process utilizing Git version control to ensure seamless code merges
- Focused on agile methodology, daily stand-ups and regular planning meetings
- Proven commitment to collaborative workflow utilizing pair programming, affinity groups and regular team stand-ups

Current Conditions – currentcondtions.herokuapp.com

Rails application built for boaters & fisherman utilizing call to USGS API for up to date conditions on any river in continental United States

28 Day Hug – www.github.com/patrickmnts/28hugs

Restructured pre-existing e-commerce site from WordPress to Rails utilizing Stripe API for payment processing and scheduling

Wilderness Aware Rafting – Buena Vista, CO

Summers of 2011 - 2012

White Water Guide

Crag Law Center - Portland, OR

12/2011 - 06/2011

Paralegal Intern/Volunteer

 Researched and prepared written summaries of federal and state laws relating to specific Northwest environmental issues facing trial

Oregon Bus Project - Portland, OR

10/2011 - 06/2011

Development Intern/Volunteer

· Organized and recruited teams of high school students in a pioneering program

Education

Portland Code School

06/13 - 08/13

Web development & programming

University of Oregon

2006 - 2010

B.S. in Political Science, Minors in Business & Economics